Ricardo Estevan

restevan@gmail.com

Profile

Organized and effective leadership skills. Proven teamwork and group communication experience.

Skills

Leadership • Teamwork • Team Management • Organizational Development • Microsoft Azure • SharePoint • SharePoint Development • Sharepoint Framework (SPFx) • Azure DevOps • Javascript • HTML • CSS • NodeJS • React

Education

The University of Texas Rio Grande Valley

Master of Science - MS, Information Technology 2015 - 2017

The University of Texas-Pan American

Bachelor of Business Administration - BBA, Business Administration and Management, 2008 - 2013

Integrity School

1998 - 2007

Certifications

Microsoft Certified: Azure FundamentalsMicrosoft 365 Certified: Fundamentals

Experience

SharePoint Administrator

McAllen ISD

Oct 2019 - Present

Designed and developed SharePoint architecture and governance plan for McAllen ISD for more than 100 communication sites and team sites to facilitate team collaboration, simplify project management and streamline document management.

- Developed and customized RBAC's, 365 groups, retention policies for SharePoint.
- Designed Team sites and Communication sites templates with the usage of SharePoint/Office 365
 Dev Patterns & Practices (PnP) Powershell and SPFx Framework to build modern web parts.

- Developed custom apps with Power Apps and automated workflows with Power Automate integrated with SharePoint.
- Assisted with SharePoint troubleshooting technical issues and conducted virtual trainings to Sharepoint site Admins with best practices for their site.

Google Workspace for Education Administrator

McAllen ISD

Oct 2019 - Present

Oversee the Google Admin console for the student domain with 20,000+ students and 4,000+ staff members.

- Manage user accounts, groups, security settings, access permissions, and device management.
- Developed custom LDAP queries using Google Cloud Directory Sync for efficient account provisioning and licensing.
- Created JavaScript scripts with Google Apps Script to automate object (device) movement between organizational units based on status.
- Implemented dynamic device enablement and disablement based on imported data.
- Implemented data loss prevention (DLP) rules and configured policy alerts to ensure compliance and enhance security.

Systems Administrator

CAPA

Jul 2017 - Oct 2019

Built data backups and disaster recovery operations plans.

- Maintained and administered Command Alkon Server Application server and database server.
- Develop custom reports with SQL queries
- Developed an intranet with communication sites for company's departments. Created team sites templates and managed them with PnP Powershell.Managed document libraries and repositories.
- Developed PowerApps custom app for sales team and automated tasks for the company with Power Automate.
- Trained and supported SharePoint users and provide SharePoint best practices.